The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Knight of the Ribbon,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Twenty-Second Episode
A New King
I would be capable of doing it,
if I really wanted to do it!
Until now I have been
so lacking in initiative and lazy.
Now I have decided
that I have courage!
Doctor Uranaru, today I have decided:
I will proclaim things that
tomorrow everyone will be surprised by!
Doctor, wait anxiously
for tomorrow to arrive.
Your Majesty, would you please tell me,
what you intend to proclaim?
I cannot, it is a secret.
Now, Uranaru, leave me alone.
Go away, quickly! Come on!
Yes, yes, Your Majesty!
I wanted to change
that old law of Silverland
that forbids a woman
from becoming King...
...and ruling the country.
It was about time to put an end...
...to these stupid
discriminations, of course.
There, it's done.
Afterwards, I want to change all
the bad laws into good laws!
But what's happening?!
What are you doing?!
Who are you?
Let go of me!
Prince! Prince!
Prince, this is a good one!
The King is nowhere to be found!
- What?!
- He can't be found!
He hasn't been seen anywhere
since this morning!
How is Mother?
How are the others?
They are desperately searching for the King!
Your Majesty! Your Majesty!
- But where is the King?!
- Where is the King?
Search for him again!
On every floor! Quickly!
Go! Your Majesty!
Father, where are you?
- Your Majesty!
Your Majesty!
Prince, we have searched for him
in every corner of the castle,
- But we didn't find him!
- Inspect the moat!
Yes, Prince!
Your Majesty, the King
remained writing something...
...for a long time, alone!
If something bad
were to happen to him..!
I'm going to look for him again, mother!
I imagine you are
very worried!
Anyway, it is very strange that the King
disappeared like this, all of a sudden.
- Isn't that right?
- Don't say useless things!
I'm going to look for
him too, Your Majesty!
Father! Father!
Father, where are you?
Father, where are you? Father!
He's not here...
That armor...
Father!
Could he be in the tomb of the
ancestors? But that's impossible...!
Father! Father!
I heard a noise!
Father!
It must have been an illusion...
- What?!
- Prince!
There is a man who claims
to have seen the King...
...early this morning!
- What? Where?
- In the northern part of the valley.
- Alright, I'm going to check!
Opal, go to the northern valley!
Father!
Opal! What is wrong with you?
What?!
That shoe looks like my father's!
Opal, hold the end
of this rope in your mouth! I'm going down!
What's wrong, Opal?
Opal!
This is dad's shoe!
Just as I thought...!
Darling!
I am truly very sorry.
Mother!
Father! Why did you die?!
Grand Duke, since the King is dead,
the Prince will ascend the throne
in a week.
The new King! King Sapphire!
If our plan goes well
until that moment...
It will be very interesting
to wait and see!
- What are you laughing at, idiot?!
- But I...
- Sapphire, it's me.
- Please, come in.
Mother, what do you think?
You are beautiful, Sapphire
Did you think I was crying?
Yes. I came to comfort you
From now on, I won't cry anymore.
Instead, I was getting dressed.
And why is that, dear?
This is the last time
that I can dress like this.
- What?!
- If I become King,
I'll never be able to wear
a dress like this again.
- Then wear it as if it were
the last. - All right, mother.
Nurse, are you there?
Oh, yes!
I was helping her get dressed!
Nurse, please don't cry!
- Now give me a smile!
- How can I not cry?!
Sapphire, this won't be
the last time you dress like this.
- What?!
- When you become King,
you can modify the law
and make a new one,
so that everyone, even women,
can become King.
I understand! I'll be able to be King
even though I'm a girl!
I will do it!
The coronation ceremony
will take place tomorrow.
The preparations are almost complete
A large delegation has arrived
from all parts of the world.
I think Prince Sapphire
has settled down...
...and is waiting for dawn.
God, please give me strength!
I'm afraid of becoming King! I fear it!
Soon the sun will rise.
God, please protect me!
Pharmacist, haven't you
made that medicine yet?
It's almost finished. In
three hours it will be ready.
Hurry up or we won't make it in
time for the coronation ceremony.
We'll make it in time, we'll make it
in time for the coronation ceremony!
- But does it really work?
- All it takes is for someone...
...to take just a little of it
to say everything they think.
If we don't make it in time,
you will die! Understood?
I will wait here
until you have finished.
Come on, hurry up!
How violent you are!
I've gotten very thirsty.
- Drink a little from that flask.
- Yes.
But what did you make me drink?
Calm down,
there's nothing to worry about!
But I'm swelling up!
I'm going to burst!
No, don't fear!
Now I will give you a good remedy right away.
- Yes, but hurry!
- Here, drink!
- You cursed wretch!
- Now stay calm and rest!
Let me work in peace
until I am finished!
Let the coronation ceremony begin..
..of Prince Sapphire!
Everything will be fine..
Now the grand coronation ceremony begins!
Here, many representatives are gathered.
...who have come from all parts of the world!
They are waiting for the Prince!
When Prince Sapphire sits on the throne,
he will be the new King of Silverland!
Here comes Grand Duke Duralumin!
Dad, I'm hungry!
Shut up!
Soon there will be the banquet!
Idiot..! And stop it!
Here, I'll give you this sweet!
Here comes the Queen!
Sapphire, the ceremony will go well.
- But where is Nylon?
- He hasn't arrived yet, sir
But what is he doing?!
Our Archbishop
is arriving!
And here comes
Prince Sapphire!
Let the coronation ceremony
begin!
One, two, three... My God!
There are a hundred diamonds!
Oh, no! No! No! I say that there
are at least two hundred of them!
- Bravo!
- Shut up!
- Grand Duke, Nylon is back!
- Really?
Tell him to put that
medicine in the Queen's wine!
The Grand Duke has ordered to
put the medicine in the Queen's wine!
Come on, quick, give it to me!
- What?! No! I won't give it to you!
- Why not?
I brought it and I
want to put it in myself.
...in the Queen's wine!
Damn it!
No, you must rest!
I told you I'll do it!
And I told you that
I will do it! Go away!
- You must rest! Understood?
- I don't care!
And now, let the toast begin!
Everyone, pour wine
into your glasses!
Grand Duke Duralumin,
please, start the toast!
Just a moment! Is
this the Queen's glass?
- Yes, sir.
- Ah, excellent!
We did it!
And now let us toast to the
health of King Sapphire of Silverland!
- Cheers!
- Hooray!
Cheers!
Long live our King!
Grand Duke Duralumin
looks strange!
I wonder why...
Mother!
Someone escort the
Queen to her room!
It's nothing, dear! It's nothing!
It's just that I didn't know it
was so bitter to hide the truth!
- Mother!
- Now everyone pay attention...
... and listen to me, because
I will tell you everything!
What is happening, Queen?
Sapphire is my daughter!
Sapphire is a girl!
Yes, Sapphire is a girl!
To make her King,
we deceived you...
...and we publicly
passed her off as a boy!
You all heard! You
are all witnesses!
This mother and her
daughter have lied...
...and have deceived
the people for 13 years!
They are cowards who
have deceived good people!
- Oh, no! Did I say something?
- Mother, it's too late!
What?!
It's true: it's too late now!
You have confessed
everything! Soldiers, arrest them!
And also arrest their
three accomplices!
As punishment, I order
them to be locked up
...in the coffin
tower until they die!
- Is there anyone who opposes?
- The coffin tower?!
Until we die?!
And their three accomplices,
as punishment for helping them,
- will be slaves!
- Slaves?! - Slaves?
One more thing:
I have decided that my son Plastic
...will become the new King!
- What? Plastic the new King?!
But it's not possible! He's an idiot!
Plastic will be the King!
Is there anyone who wants to oppose?
And now take away
those vile traitors!
Princess Sapphire and Queen,
it is unpleasant, I know,
but please get into
the prisoners' carriage!
Let's go, Mother.
Sapphire, please, forgive me!
You have been trapped
by Duralumin, Mother.
I think you drank
some drugged wine.
I will never see you again, I think.
Then farewell! Farewell!
This is the Coffin Tower.
Princess Sapphire, Queen,
I am sorry,
but once
you are locked in there,
You will never be able to get out of it again.
Prepare yourselves.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP